coursehero.com 2019-06-30

# Course Hero - Privacy Policy

__ Last updated May 17, 2019

This Privacy Policy applies to www.coursehero.com owned and operated by Course Hero, Inc. Course Hero's Privacy Policy is designed to help you understand how we collect and use the personal information you decide to share, and help you make informed decisions when using Course Hero located at www.coursehero.com (the "Website"). 

By using or accessing the Website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

######  Information we collect

When you visit the Website you provide us with two types of information: (i) personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected by us and (ii) use information collected by us as you interact with the Website. 

When you register with the Website, you provide us with certain personal information, such as your name, your email address, your school, your status, your major, your graduation year, as well as sensitive information such as credit card information and any other personal or preference information that you provide to us. 

######  Tracking technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by the Website and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the Website, tracking users’ movements around the Website and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our Website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our Website may be limited. 

######  Log files

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or Website functionality. 

######  Behavioral targeting / re-targeting

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this Website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads. 

######  Local storage objects (HTML5)

We and third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our Website or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information. 

Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. 

######  Use of information obtained by the website

We use this information to: 

  * Fulfill your order 
  * Send you an order confirmation 
  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products 
  * Send you requested product or service information 
  * Send product updates or warranty information 
  * Respond to customer service requests 
  * Administer your account 
  * Send you periodical email newsletters about joint ventures, significant updates to the Website or marketing communications 
  * Send you marketing communications 

  * Administer contests and sweepstakes you entered, and notify you if you won 
  * Respond to your questions and concerns 
  * Improve our Website and marketing efforts 
  * Conduct research and analysis 
  * Display content based upon your interests 
  * Facilitate your transactions with other users 
  * Enable you to post your resume, search job postings, and contact or be contacted by prospective employers 
  * List you in our member directory made available only to other members 
  * List you in our publicly accessible member directory. If you do not want to be listed in our directory contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 

######  Choice/opt-out

You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 

We enable you to create a profile, and share information such as messages, photos, and videos with others. Please note that we cannot control the actions of others with whom you may choose to share your pages and information. 

When you register with the Website, you create your own account. Your username and email will be attached to material you upload on the Website. The Website will not provide any of your other personal information to third parties. 

When you disclose your Facebook account email address and password to the Website on the Invite Friends page, the Website will only use such information to (i) add you to the Facebook group named "Course Hero Inc." and (ii) invite your Facebook friends to join the Facebook group named "Course Hero Inc." All such Facebook transmissions using your Facebook password are automatically performed over a secure, encrypted connection. The Website does not store your Facebook password. 

######  Information sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this Privacy Policy. Except as set forth below, we do not sell, share, rent or trade your personal information to third parties for their promotional purposes. 

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

We may also disclose your personal information 

  * in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. 
  * as required by law such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; 
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request; 

  * if Course Hero is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership; or 
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so. 

We may share your personal information with other companies so that they can market their products or services to you. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 

We make your contact information available to other users that you transact with on this Website to help complete the transaction. 

######  Links

The Website may contain links to other websites. The Website is of course not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. The Website encourages users to be aware when they leave the Website to read the privacy policy of each and every website that collects personal information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Website. 

######  Blog

Our Website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

######  Changing or removing information

Upon request Course Hero will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. To request this information please complete this form, contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com) with a link to the identified material/content. We will respond to your request within 5 business days. 

Users may modify, delete or remove any of their account information at any time by logging into the My Account page. Information will be updated immediately. Individuals who wish to deactivate their Website account may do so on the My Account page. 

######  Protecting information and security

The Website takes appropriate precautions to protect our users' information. Your account information is located on a secured server behind a firewall. Because email and instant messaging are not recognized as secure communications, the Website requests that you not send private information to us by email. 

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Website, you can contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 

######  Data retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

######  Referrals

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Website. Course Hero stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. 

Your friend may contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com) to request that we remove this information from our database. 

######  Social media widgets

Our Website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Website. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

######  Single sign on

You can log in to our Website using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form.  Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Website to your profile page to share with others within your network. 

######  Public profile

The profile you create on our Website will be publicly accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy settings of your profile through your account portal. If you wish to request removal of your information from our directory, you can contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 

######  Unauthorized profile

To remove unauthorized profiles, please send an email to [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 

######  Changes in this privacy policy

If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will alert you to changes by email and/or by placing a notice on our home page and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. 

######  Age restriction

If you are under 13 years of age, then please do not use or access the Website at any time or in any manner. If Course Hero learns that personal information of persons under 13 years of age has been collected through the Website, then Course Hero will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. 

######  Contact us

Course Hero, Inc.  
2000 Seaport Blvd, Floor 3  
Redwood City, CA 94063  
866-634-9397  

#####  EU Residents

If you are a resident of the European Union (“EU”), United Kingdom, Lichtenstein, Norway, or Iceland, you may have additional rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”) with respect to your Personal Data, as outlined below. 

For this section, we use the terms “Personal Data” and “processing” as they are defined in the GDPR, but “Personal Data” generally means information that can be used to individually identify a person, and “processing” generally covers actions that can be performed in connection with data such as collection, use, storage and disclosure. Company will be the controller of your Personal Data processed in connection with the Website. 

Where applicable, this GDPR Privacy Notice is intended to supplement, and not replace, the Company’s Privacy Policy. If there are any conflicts between this section and any other provision of this Privacy Policy, the policy or portion that is more protective of Personal Data shall control to the extent of such conflict. If you have any questions about this section or whether any of the following applies to you, please contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 

**What Personal Data Do We Collect From You?** We collect Personal Data about you when you provide such information directly to us, when third parties such as our business partners or service providers provide us with Personal Data about you, or when Personal Data about you is automatically collected in connection with your use of our Website. 

_Information we collect directly from you_ : We receive Personal Data directly from you when you provide us with such Personal Data. For example, you provide us with your username, email address, and/or Facebook user ID when you login into the Website. When you pay for certain Course Hero features, you provide us with Personal Data such as your name, credit card information, PayPal information, address, and other payment related information. If you populate your Course Hero profile, you might provide us information including your first and last name, phone number, gender, year of birth, graduation year, academic major, profile picture, and current and past school and course information. Finally, if you receive payments from Course Hero, you would provide us with additional Personal Data including your tax address and tax identification number. 

_Information we automatically collect when you use our Website_ : When you use the Website, we automatically collect some information such as your IP address, browser and computer information such as browser type, version, operating system, time zone setting, cookie number, and your device ID. We collect information about your usage of Course Hero such as the pages or content you view, your searches, and other actions. 

**How Do We Use Your Personal Data?** We process Personal Data to operate, improve, understand and personalize our Website. For example, we use Personal Data to: 

  * Create and manage user profiles 
  * Communicate with you about the Website 
  * Process orders 
  * Contact you about Service announcements, updates or offers 
  * Provide support and assistance for the Website 
  * Improve and/or personalize website content and communications 
  * Meet contract or legal obligations 
  * Respond to user inquiries 
  * Fulfill user requests 
  * Comply with our legal or contractual obligations 
  * Resolve disputes 
  * Protect against or deter fraudulent, illegal or harmful actions 
  * Enforce our Terms of Service 

We will only process your Personal Data if we have a lawful basis for doing so. Lawful bases for processing include consent, contractual necessity and our “legitimate interests” or the legitimate interest of others, as further described below. 

  * **Contractual Necessity:** We process Personal Data as a matter of “contractual necessity”, meaning that we need to process the data to perform under our Terms of Use with you, which enables us to provide you with the Website. When we process data due to contractual necessity, failure to provide such Personal Data will result in your inability to use some or all portions of the Website that require such data. 
  * **Legitimate Interest:** We process the other Personal Data listed above when we believe it furthers the legitimate interest of us or third parties. 

Examples of these legitimate interests include: 

    * Operation and improvement of our business, products and services 
    * Marketing of our products and services 
    * Provision of customer support 
    * Protection from fraud or security threats 
    * Compliance with legal obligations 
    * Completion of corporate transactions 

  * **Consent:** In some cases, we process Personal Data based on the consent you expressly grant to us at the time we collect such data. When we process Personal Data based on your consent, it will be expressly indicated to you at the point and time of collection. 
  * **Other Processing Grounds:** From time to time we may also need to process Personal Data to comply with a legal obligation, if it is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or other data subjects, or if it is necessary for a task carried out in the public interest. 

**How and With Whom Do We Share Your Data?** We share Personal Data with vendors, third party service providers and agents who work on our behalf and provide us with services related to the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Service. These parties may include: 

  * Payment processors 
  * Fraud prevention service providers 
  * Ad networks 
  * Analytics service providers 
  * Staff augmentation and contract personnel 
  * Hosting service providers 
  * Co-location service providers 
  * Telecommunications service providers 
  * Financial and tax audit service providers 

We also share Personal Data when necessary to complete a transaction initiated or authorized by you or provide you with a product or service you have requested. In addition to those set forth above, these parties also include: 

  * Other users (where you post information publicly or as otherwise necessary to effect a transaction initiated or authorized by you through the Website) 
  * Social media services (if you interact with them through your use of the Website) 
  * Third party business partners who you access through the Website 
  * Other parties authorized by you 

We also share Personal Data when we believe it is necessary to: 

  * Comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal process, including from law enforcement or other government agencies 
  * Protect us, our business or our users, for example to enforce our terms of service, prevent spam or other unwanted communications and investigate or protect against fraud 
  * Maintain the security of our products and services 

We also share information with third parties when you give us consent to do so. 

Last, we share Personal Data with our affiliates or other members of our corporate family. Furthermore, if we choose to buy or sell assets, user information is typically one of the transferred business assets. Moreover, if we, or substantially all of our assets, were acquired, or if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party, and we would share Personal Data with the party that is acquiring our assets. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of us or our assets may continue to use your Personal Information as set forth in this policy. 

**How Long Do We Retain Your Personal Data?** We retain Personal Data about you for as long as you have an open account with us or as otherwise necessary to provide you the Website. In some cases we retain Personal Data for longer, if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes or collect fees owed, or is otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. Afterwards, we retain some information in a depersonalized or aggregated form but not in a way that would identify you personally. 

**What Security Measures Do We Use?** We seek to protect Personal Data using appropriate technical and organizational measures based on the type of Personal Data and applicable processing activity. 

**Personal Data of Children:** As noted in the Terms of Use, we do not knowingly collect or solicit Personal Data from anyone under the age of 13. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for the Website or send any Personal Data about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected Personal Data from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us Personal Data, please contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 

**What Rights Do You Have Regarding Your Personal Data?** You have certain rights with respect to your Personal Data, including those set forth below. Please note that in some circumstances, we may not be able to fully comply with your request, such as if it is frivolous or extremely impractical, if it jeopardizes the rights of others, or if it is not required by law, but in those circumstances, we will still respond to notify you of such a decision. In some cases, we may also need to you to provide us with additional information, which may include Personal Data, if necessary to verify your identity and the nature of your request. 

  * **Access:** You can request more information about the Personal Data we hold about you and request a copy of such Personal Data. You can also access certain of your Personal Data by emailing [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 
  * **Rectification:** If you believe that any Personal Data we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request that we correct or supplement such data. You can correct some of this information directly by emailing [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com). 
  * Erasure: You can request that we erase some or all of your Personal Data from our systems. 
  * **Withdrawal of Consent:** If we are processing your Personal Data based on your consent (as indicated at the time of collection of such data), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note, however, that if you exercise this right, you may have to then provide express consent on a case-by-case basis for the use or disclosure of certain of your Personal Data, if such use or disclosure is necessary to enable you to utilize some or all of our Website. 
  * **Portability:** You can ask for a copy of your Personal Data in a machine-readable format. You can also request that we transmit the data to another controller where technically feasible. 
  * **Objection:** You can contact us to let us know that you object to the further use or disclosure of your Personal Data for certain purposes, such as for direct marketing purposes. 
  * **Restriction of Processing:** You can ask us to restrict further processing of your Personal Data. Right to File Complaint: You have the right to lodge a complaint about Company’s practices with respect to your Personal Data with the supervisory authority of your country or EU Member State. 

**Transfers of Personal Data:** The Website is hosted and operated in the United States (“U.S.”) through Company and its service providers, and if you do not reside in the U.S., laws in the U.S. may differ from the laws where you reside. By using the Website, you acknowledge that any Personal Data about you, regardless of whether provided by you or obtained from a third party, is being provided to Company in the U.S. and will be hosted on U.S. servers, and you authorize Company to transfer, store and process your information to and in the U.S., and possibly other countries. You hereby consent to the transfer of your data to the U.S. pursuant to EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, the details of which are further set forth below. 

Company has certified to the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection and use of Personal Data transferred from the EU, the United Kingdom, and/or Switzerland. For more information about the Privacy Shield Program, and to view Company’s certification, please visit www.privacyshield.gov. Company is committed to the Privacy Shield Principles of (1) notice, (2) consent, (3) accountability for onward transfer, (4) security, (5) data integrity and purpose limitation, (6) access and (7) recourse, enforcement and liability with respect to all Personal Data received from within the EU in reliance on the Privacy Shield. The Privacy Shield Principles require that we remain potentially liable if any third party processing Personal Data on our behalf fails to comply with these Privacy Shield Principles (except to the extent we are not responsible for the event giving rise to any alleged damage). Company’s compliance with the Privacy Shield is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. 

Please contact us at [privacy@coursehero.com](mailto:privacy@coursehero.com) with any questions or concerns relating to our Privacy Shield Certification. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>. 

Under certain conditions, you may also be entitled to invoke binding arbitration for complaints not resolved by other means. 

**What If You Have Questions Regarding Your Personal Data?** If you have any questions about this section or our data practices generally, please contact us using the following information: 

Mailing address: 

Course Hero - Privacy  
2000 Seaport Blvd, Floor 3  
Redwood City, CA 94063 

| 

Email Address: 

---|---  
  
Individuals in the EU may contact our EU representative according to Art. 27 GDPR regarding all requests related to data protection and privacy: 

DP-Dock GmbH  
Course Hero, Inc.  
Ballindamm 39  
20095 Hamburg  
E-Mail: [coursehero@gdpr-rep.com](mailto:coursehero@gdpr-rep.com)
